<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consulting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/activities/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2008 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/activities/consulting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;System Administration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have years of experience in building secure and robust system in Linux/Unix
environments and we can offer consulting for searching and resolve bottlenecks
and deployment issues. We have &lt;strong&gt;RedHat&lt;/strong&gt; Certified Engineers as part of our
staff and we can support our Customers on migrating existing infrastuctures in
the cloud, particularly on platforms like &lt;strong&gt;Amazon AWS&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Heroku&lt;/strong&gt; and
&lt;strong&gt;OpenShift&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Quality Assurance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We guarantee the overall quality of our softwares using well known Testing
frameworks and we can support Customers on incrementing Test coverage of
existing software systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Software Configuration Management&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We offer support for every aspect of SCM: our main tool for revision control is
Git but we can help handle and migrate from and to other system like Mercurial
or SVN.
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rhce.png&#34; alt=&#34;RHCE&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/activities/workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/activities/workshop/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The way Evonove grows ideas and projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Events&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The space at the 2nd floor is equipped with desks, chairs, whiteboards and a
videoprojector - a nice environment where performing technical meetings,
interactive tracks, seminars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evonove provides professional training on methodologies and technologies for
companies and single professionals. Periodically Evonove hosts and organizes
seminars about open source technologies free of charges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Internships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the collaboration of the University of Perugia we offer internships for
students and graduates in the field of Information Technology. Evonove
encourages students to work on open source projects and supports them on
the adoption of bleeding edge technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Sponsorships&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evonove endorses small projects in the open source world, in particular
the &lt;code&gt;Python User Group of Perugia &amp;lt;http://pypg.org&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django OAuth Toolkit is out!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/django-oauth-toolkit-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/django-oauth-toolkit-is-out/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We just released the &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/django-oauth-toolkit/0.3.0&#34;&gt;latest version&lt;/a&gt; of Django OAuth Toolkit,
a library to add OAuth goodies to Django projects. The project is under active development, at the moment it offers
fully-featured and RFC6749 compliant OAuth2 providers implementation and it runs on Django 1.4, 1.5 and 1.6a1 with
Python 2.7 and 3.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;A brief history&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything started when we found ourselves in the need to implement an OAuth2 provider for a Django web service.
We happily use Django REST framework wherever we have to expose an API, and that was right the case. Django REST framework
has built-in support for a third party Django app implementing OAuth providers but we shortly faced some issues and
started to search for an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digging around we stumbled upon this blog post from Daniel Greenfeld:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://pydanny.com/the-sorry-state-of-python-oauth-providers.html&#34;&gt;The sorry state of Python OAuth providers&lt;/a&gt;. Enough
is enough but we were still not sure whether starting another project from scratch or not, when we met Daniel at the Django
Circus in Warsaw. We talked shortly about the topic but he was very convincing and we started coding as soon as we came
back at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re trying to involve other people in the project and usually this is the first question we&amp;rsquo;re asked: why another
project? Instead of complaining about other projects, we usually list what we got so far and possibly other don&amp;rsquo;t have:
features and goodies we strongly needed and now actually have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;DRY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/idan/oauthlib&#34;&gt;oauthlib&lt;/a&gt; is currently the state of the art OAuth library in the Python
world. We choose to rely on a well documented, well supported and active project instead of write one on our own, with
all the FUD of the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OAuth protocol can be quite mind boggling every here and there. We think writing good docs is mandatory when the code
may be quite simple but the workflow heavily complicated. We are also putting a lot of efforts on writing tutorials, as
one line of code worths thousand words (expecially with OAuth workflows :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not referring to Unit testing here (still we do our best to keep coverage over 95% ;-) but to some stuff users
can actually use to test their applications on a real OAuth2 workflow. In some circumstances, OAuth2 applications need
a companion to exchange tokens, provide authorizations and so on. We deployed an OAuth2 playground on Heroku to let
users perform a roundtrip between their local apps and a real server (or client, depending on the case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Timezone aware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe that if your dates and times are not timezone aware, they&amp;rsquo;re broken. That said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Python 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the neverending effort of porting our codebase to Python 3, we cannot rely anymore on libraries and tools which do
not have at least any roadmap for the porting. Django OAuth Toolkit is alredy working with both Python 2.7 and 3.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re working hard on the project also because we&amp;rsquo;re using it internally in our company, so we can guarantee our full
support on the middle term and hopefully longer, depending on the success it could be have in the Django world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;We want you!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As any other Open Source project, we&amp;rsquo;re nothing without a community: any help is appreciated, code of course but also
docs, testing and any kind of feedback. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/evonove/django-oauth-toolkit&#34;&gt;Fork the project&lt;/a&gt;,
take a ride, fill some PRs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Python desktop application with Jenkins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/build-python-desktop-application-with-jenkins/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/build-python-desktop-application-with-jenkins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently started using &lt;a href=&#34;http://jenkins-ci.org/&#34;&gt;Jenkins&lt;/a&gt;, a well known system for Continuous Integration,
and make it perform tasks like build and package multiplatform desktop
applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re currently in charge of developing a desktop application written in &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;strong&gt;Qt framework&lt;/strong&gt;.
Though small, the application is quite complex and has a lot of dependencies which is quite easy to satisfy on a local
environment (provided that you&amp;rsquo;re not on Windows, but that&amp;rsquo;s another story).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several proprietary &lt;strong&gt;C/C++&lt;/strong&gt; libraries involved, and some of them are under active development, so we have to
stay up to date with them and with the relative Python bindings. At an early stage of the development the environment
was entirely hand crafted, so building and packaging the software with the right configuration was up to the single
developer who wrote the first draft of the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prototype was ok, so we started a refactoring of the codebase and assigned other resources to the project. Problems
with the building environment arose almost instantly: not every developer works on the same configuration (and this is
a choice) and maintaining different build scripts was not acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We needed a build system and we needed it fast, so we started reviewing all of these:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gnu Make&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.fabfile.org/en/latest/&#34;&gt;Fabric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://paver.github.io/paver/&#34;&gt;Paver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.buildout.org/en/latest/&#34;&gt;buildout&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cmake.org/&#34;&gt;CMake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CMake seems the most flexible of the above (at least for a newcomer) and it was the only one which let us collect the code
from several sources &lt;strong&gt;(CVS repos, git repos, source tarballs)&lt;/strong&gt; build it with different build systems &lt;strong&gt;(Make, QMake, distutils,
custom scripts)&lt;/strong&gt;, make the executable with PyInstaller and create the archive to distribute. First issue solved:
developers can now build the software with minimum effort and in a well defined and versioned environment&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the real issue, beta tester started asking for packages for their own distributions/OSs - we needed a build
system capable to run our CMake script on several machines, produce the software package and make it available for download
somewhere on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our requirements:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a turnkey solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should be able to start and stop virtual machines inside our LAN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;should be able to start and stop EC2 machines&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;can speak with cloud storaging systems (e.g. S3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We briefly reviewed two products, Jenkins and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cdash.org/&#34;&gt;CDash&lt;/a&gt;, and we ended up with &lt;strong&gt;Jenkins&lt;/strong&gt;
basically for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;huge amount of very useful plugins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easy installation and maintaining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment we have a master/slave installation on Jenkins running on a physical machine and several slave nodes with
different Linux distributions (both physical and virtual) where the git repository containing the CMake builder is cloned,
run, and the final product is actually produced. Jenkins can remotely control &lt;strong&gt;KVM&lt;/strong&gt; virtual machines, starting and stopping
them depending on its needs. Artifacts produced by the builders (i.e. the tarballs containing the software package ready
to be shipped) are collected and uploaded to a &lt;strong&gt;S3 bucket&lt;/strong&gt;, where authorized beta testers can download them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feel free to drop here a comment&lt;/strong&gt; and share your experience, it&amp;rsquo;s never easy finding a best practice when the requirements
are complex and not always well defined as they are in this case.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DjangoCon Europe 2013 Wrap-up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/djangocon-europe-2013-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/djangocon-europe-2013-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seriously, a circus? That perfectly fits the quote &lt;em&gt;And now for something completely different&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just got back from the latest DjangoCon Europe - I usually write a sort of log of the conferences I attend, this time
it&amp;rsquo;ll be just a matter of thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2013/circus.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;circus&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to the organizers&lt;/strong&gt;, they possibly delivered the craziest tech conference I ever attended. Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;food&lt;/strong&gt;,
I much appreciated the veg option (I arrived in Warsaw prepared to starve, likely I gained weight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2013/food.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;food&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free and fresh beverages&lt;/strong&gt; constantly available for the attendees. Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free beer&lt;/strong&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t now if and when it&amp;rsquo;ll
happen again&amp;hellip;). Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free ice creams&lt;/strong&gt;, again, constantly available during the conference. Thanks for the
&lt;strong&gt;goodies&lt;/strong&gt; (hammoks, blankets, cushions, deckchairs and so on&amp;hellip;). Thanks for bringing me to &lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;: nice people, nice
places, good food - it totally worths, even for a short weekend. Thanks to the &lt;strong&gt;speakers&lt;/strong&gt;, some of them were very
inspiring and the amount of lighting talk was ridicolously huge! Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;/staff/palazzem&#34;&gt;Emanuele&lt;/a&gt; who arranged
a very fun (and informative!) lighting talk in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2013/lighting.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;lighting&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thanks to the &lt;strong&gt;weather&lt;/strong&gt;, really don&amp;rsquo;t know what could
have been happened in case of rain :-).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DroidCon 2014, all aboard!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2014/droidcon-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2014/droidcon-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After Amsterdam, Bangalore, Berlin, Brussels, London, Murcia and Tunis the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://droidcon.com/&#34;&gt;Droidcon&lt;/a&gt; arrives in Italy, &lt;a href=&#34;http://it.droidcon.com/2014/&#34;&gt;in Turin&lt;/a&gt;.
It&amp;rsquo;ll be two days of talks, workshops, showcases and even an Hackaton dedicated to one of the most
widespread operating system in the world: Android.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/2014/droidcon.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;droidcon&#34; /&gt;

At Droidcon you can see Android in action in every field of application: mobile devices, of course,
but even TV, cars, gaming and embedded systems. And we&amp;rsquo;ll be there just to cover the latter: with
a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.udoo.org/&#34;&gt;Udoo board&lt;/a&gt; attached to a custom motorized rover,
&lt;a href=&#34;/staff/palazzem&#34;&gt;Emanuele&lt;/a&gt; is going to show off Android&amp;rsquo;s potential pushing it beyond the
comfort of mobile devices with the talk &lt;a href=&#34;http://it.droidcon.com/2014/lineup/&#34;&gt;Release the Kraken&lt;/a&gt;
The Internet of Things seems to be very attractive these days, people want to get their hands dirty
with the bare metal and media grasped the potential of the makers revolution, as you can see on
&lt;a href=&#34;http://nova.ilsole24ore.com/esperienze/android-piu-open&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;appeared on one of the
most authoritative business newspaper (only available in italian).
You can learn more on Emanuele&amp;rsquo;s adventure at the Droidcon in
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techmate.it/droidcon/&#34;&gt;this interview&lt;/a&gt;(again, only in italian) published on the electronic
magazine &lt;strong&gt;Techmate&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Callout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/callout/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/callout/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;.. |callout| image:: /img/tofu_logo.png&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Tofu, file storage made easy &amp;lt;http://tofu.st/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;|callout| Tofu is a file storage solution based on evonove&amp;rsquo;s own customers
requirements. You can try the service and get 1Gb of disk space for your personal
files, for free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. raw:: html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://tofu.st&amp;quot; target=&amp;quot;_blank&amp;quot; class=&amp;quot;btn btn-warning&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;i class=&amp;quot;icon-shopping-cart&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;Get an account now&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/django/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/django/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Django is a full stack, open source web framework written in Python
finalized to the development of complex web applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evonove can help customers on planning and developing Django projects
and is active in the community by releasing the most of the code with
an open source license and participating in several open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Django OAuth Toolkit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Django OAuth Toolkit can help you providing out of the box all the endpoints,
data and logic needed to add OAuth2 capabilities to your Django projects.
Django OAuth Toolkit makes extensive use of the excellent OAuthLib, so that
everything is rfc-compliant.
Read the docs: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://django-oauth-toolkit.readthedocs.org/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Django Stored Messages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app integrates smoothly with Django&amp;rsquo;s messages framework (django.contrib.messages),
but users can decide which messages have to be stored on the database backend and kept
available over sessions.
Read the docs: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://django-stored-messages.readthedocs.org/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Django Money Rates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currency conversion utilities for money.
Read the docs: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://django-money-rates.readthedocs.org/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europython 2013 Wrap-up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/europython-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/europython-2013/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Right back from the EuroPython conference, the last in Florence before moving to Berlin for the next two years.
It was a pretty long week, a lot of talks, people, dinners, cocktails, beers, barbecues, sprints&amp;hellip; I just want to
thank the organizers, the wifi guys, the cable guy, the personnel from the hotel, all the nice people I met and
the speakers, in particular those from evonove, who made a great job on contributing with a regular talk, a training
and a lightning talk. We also managed to make a code sprint for
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/evonove/django-oauth-toolkit&#34;&gt;Django OAuth Toolkit&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday, right after the goodbye party
(kudos for us :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the recordings of the talks provided by &lt;a href=&#34;/staff/palazzem&#34;&gt;Emanuele&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;/staff/synasius&#34;&gt;Federico&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Speed up your Django apps with Jython and SPDY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player center-block&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/DD1zLltB1RQ&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;An intro to Blender modeling and scripting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player center-block&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/4e6z3Ada00I&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player center-block&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/U1K19GoLMuk&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;An intro to Blender modeling and scripting - Reprise&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;embed video-player&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe class=&#34;youtube-player center-block&#34; type=&#34;text/html&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;385&#34; src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/embed/96WoCShO3i0&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the lightning talks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/iUNbgNuN0qY?t=1h9m32s&#34;&gt;youtube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contacts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contacts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;col-wrapper&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;row main-block&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;contact-info span3&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Evonove SRL&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;!-- COMPANY ADDRESS --&gt;
        &lt;address&gt;
            Via Fra&#39; Filippo Longo 16/b,&lt;br&gt;
            Magione (PG) - ITALY&lt;br&gt;
            Phone: +39 075 843667&lt;br&gt;
            Fax: +39 075 843667&lt;br&gt;
            Email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:info@evonove.it&#34;&gt;info@evonove.it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
            Web: &lt;a href=&#34;http://evonove.it&#34;&gt;evonove.it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
            Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/evonove&#34;&gt;@evonove&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;/address&gt;
            &lt;hr/&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;span9&#34;&gt;
            &lt;!-- GOOGLE MAP --&gt;
            &lt;iframe style=&#34;width: 100%; height: 600px; border: none;&#34; src=&#34;https://maps.google.it/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=s_q&amp;amp;hl=it&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=evonove&amp;amp;aq=&amp;amp;sll=42.990899,12.578031&amp;amp;sspn=3.945505,8.453979&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=evonove&amp;amp;hnear=&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;cid=12213368677978933014&amp;amp;ll=43.192662,12.254562&amp;amp;spn=0.225271,0.411301&amp;amp;z=11&amp;amp;iwloc=A&amp;amp;output=embed&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.google.it/maps?f=q&amp;amp;source=embed&amp;amp;hl=it&amp;amp;geocode=&amp;amp;q=evonove&amp;amp;aq=&amp;amp;sll=42.990899,12.578031&amp;amp;sspn=3.945505,8.453979&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;hq=evonove&amp;amp;hnear=&amp;amp;t=m&amp;amp;cid=12213368677978933014&amp;amp;ll=43.192662,12.254562&amp;amp;spn=0.225271,0.411301&amp;amp;z=11&amp;amp;iwloc=A&#34; style=&#34;color:#0000FF;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Visualizzazione ingrandita della mappa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Visualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/molecular-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/molecular-visualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/pymol2.png&#34; alt=&#34;pymol&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;|pymol| We support our customers providing 3D programming consultancy with a
particular focus on the field of molecular visualization, using open source
tools and libraries like PyMol and VTK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videomapping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/videomapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/videomapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Videomapping is a projection technique used to display images on irregular
surfaces so they seem to emit light instead of receiving it, as they were real
screens. Through this technique we can add value to shapes and surfaces,
perfectly fulfilling advertising and entertaining needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are specialized in mapping small and medium surfaces, goods and furnitures.
Some of our works can be found on &lt;code&gt;veedea.it &amp;lt;http://veedea.it&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ and our &lt;code&gt;Vimeo pages &amp;lt;http://vimeo.com/user11262087&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. vimeo:: 40283798
   :align: center
   :height: 375
   :width: 500
   :noportrait:
   :nobyline:
   :notitle:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/qt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/qt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/qt-logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;qtlogo&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;|qtlogo| Qt is a development framework for the creation of applications and user
interfaces for desktop, embedded and mobile platforms. Qt also provides
support for network programming, multi threading, database access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qt is our first choice when developing desktop applications or when high
performances are a requirement. We have solid experience using Qt both in C++
and Python programming languages and we can offer support even on existing
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/homepage/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Say Hello to Evonove!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;IT consulting for small and medium enterprises.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We help our customers to build quality IT systems by designing and developing
software, planning and managing infrastructures, training. We try to actively
involve our customers in every step when delivering a project, from the design
of the application to the final test. Companies with their own technical staff
can temporarily hire part of our staff when specific know-how is needed during
the development of a project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Web Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/webapps/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We make modern web applications with upstream technologies, leveraging HTML5 to
build responsive layouts, suitable for desktops and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Java Backend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We choose &lt;strong&gt;Seam&lt;/strong&gt; among the moltitude of Java framework for its original
approach to the MVC pattern. Seam respects EJB3 specification and it encourage
annotations over XML configurations, still using well known development tools
like JSF, JPA/Hibernate and JAAS. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s basically a web framework, Seam
glues together serveral technologies making the development of CRUD applications
quick, easy and attractive. We like to call Seam the &lt;em&gt;autoframework&lt;/em&gt;: you write
the models, she does the pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Backend Python&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building lightweight applications or RESTful APIs we use &lt;strong&gt;Flask&lt;/strong&gt;, a wsgi
compliant, open source micro-framework extremely flexible, perfect for agile
development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For complex web applications we prefer &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt;, a full stack web framework
which comes with a number of tools that can satisfy almost every software
requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For developing intranets, DMS or complex web portals with specific requirements
about user and roles management we use &lt;strong&gt;Plone&lt;/strong&gt;, an open source, enterprise
level CMS particularly useful in such application fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Frontend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow the living standard of HTML5 to build effective, modern and good looking
web applications. When needed, we make use of MVC Javascript frameworks like
&lt;strong&gt;EmberJS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;AngularJS&lt;/strong&gt; in conjunction with RESTful web services on the
backend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>