<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Expertise on my new hugo site </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/expertise/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Web Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/webapps/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We make modern web applications with upstream technologies, leveraging HTML5 to
build responsive layouts, suitable for desktops and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Java Backend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We choose &lt;strong&gt;Seam&lt;/strong&gt; among the moltitude of Java framework for its original
approach to the MVC pattern. Seam respects EJB3 specification and it encourage
annotations over XML configurations, still using well known development tools
like JSF, JPA/Hibernate and JAAS. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s basically a web framework, Seam
glues together serveral technologies making the development of CRUD applications
quick, easy and attractive. We like to call Seam the &lt;em&gt;autoframework&lt;/em&gt;: you write
the models, she does the pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Backend Python&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building lightweight applications or RESTful APIs we use &lt;strong&gt;Flask&lt;/strong&gt;, a wsgi
compliant, open source micro-framework extremely flexible, perfect for agile
development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For complex web applications we prefer &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt;, a full stack web framework
which comes with a number of tools that can satisfy almost every software
requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For developing intranets, DMS or complex web portals with specific requirements
about user and roles management we use &lt;strong&gt;Plone&lt;/strong&gt;, an open source, enterprise
level CMS particularly useful in such application fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Frontend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow the living standard of HTML5 to build effective, modern and good looking
web applications. When needed, we make use of MVC Javascript frameworks like
&lt;strong&gt;EmberJS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;AngularJS&lt;/strong&gt; in conjunction with RESTful web services on the
backend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>