<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Expertises on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Molecular Visualization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/molecular-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/molecular-visualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.. |pymol| image:: /img/pymol2.png
    :class: bordered-img quote-right&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;|pymol| We support our customers providing 3D programming consultancy with a
particular focus on the field of molecular visualization, using open source
tools and libraries like PyMol and VTK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/qt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/qt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.. |qtlogo| image:: /img/qt-logo.jpg
    :alt: Qt logo
    :class: quote-right bordered-img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;|qtlogo| Qt is a development framework for the creation of applications and user
interfaces for desktop, embedded and mobile platforms. Qt also provides
support for network programming, multi threading, database access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Qt is our first choice when developing desktop applications or when high
performances are a requirement. We have solid experience using Qt both in C++
and Python programming languages and we can offer support even on existing
projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/django/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/django/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Django is a full stack, open source web framework written in Python
finalized to the development of complex web applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evonove can help customers on planning and developing Django projects
and is active in the community by releasing the most of the code with
an open source license and participating in several open source projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Django OAuth Toolkit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Django OAuth Toolkit can help you providing out of the box all the endpoints,
data and logic needed to add OAuth2 capabilities to your Django projects.
Django OAuth Toolkit makes extensive use of the excellent OAuthLib, so that
everything is rfc-compliant.
Read the docs: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://django-oauth-toolkit.readthedocs.org/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Django Stored Messages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app integrates smoothly with Django&amp;rsquo;s messages framework (django.contrib.messages),
but users can decide which messages have to be stored on the database backend and kept
available over sessions.
Read the docs: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://django-stored-messages.readthedocs.org/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Django Money Rates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currency conversion utilities for money.
Read the docs: &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;https://django-money-rates.readthedocs.org/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videomapping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/videomapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/videomapping/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Videomapping is a projection technique used to display images on irregular
surfaces so they seem to emit light instead of receiving it, as they were real
screens. Through this technique we can add value to shapes and surfaces,
perfectly fulfilling advertising and entertaining needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are specialized in mapping small and medium surfaces, goods and furnitures.
Some of our works can be found on &lt;code&gt;veedea.it &amp;lt;http://veedea.it&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ and our &lt;code&gt;Vimeo pages &amp;lt;http://vimeo.com/user11262087&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. vimeo:: 40283798
   :align: center
   :height: 375
   :width: 500
   :noportrait:
   :nobyline:
   :notitle:&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Web Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/expertise/webapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/expertise/webapps/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We make modern web applications with upstream technologies, leveraging HTML5 to
build responsive layouts, suitable for desktops and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Java Backend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We choose &lt;strong&gt;Seam&lt;/strong&gt; among the moltitude of Java framework for its original
approach to the MVC pattern. Seam respects EJB3 specification and it encourage
annotations over XML configurations, still using well known development tools
like JSF, JPA/Hibernate and JAAS. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s basically a web framework, Seam
glues together serveral technologies making the development of CRUD applications
quick, easy and attractive. We like to call Seam the &lt;em&gt;autoframework&lt;/em&gt;: you write
the models, she does the pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Backend Python&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When building lightweight applications or RESTful APIs we use &lt;strong&gt;Flask&lt;/strong&gt;, a wsgi
compliant, open source micro-framework extremely flexible, perfect for agile
development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For complex web applications we prefer &lt;strong&gt;Django&lt;/strong&gt;, a full stack web framework
which comes with a number of tools that can satisfy almost every software
requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For developing intranets, DMS or complex web portals with specific requirements
about user and roles management we use &lt;strong&gt;Plone&lt;/strong&gt;, an open source, enterprise
level CMS particularly useful in such application fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Frontend&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We follow the living standard of HTML5 to build effective, modern and good looking
web applications. When needed, we make use of MVC Javascript frameworks like
&lt;strong&gt;EmberJS&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;AngularJS&lt;/strong&gt; in conjunction with RESTful web services on the
backend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>