<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Django on  </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/django/index.xml/</link>
    
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django admin e permessi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/django-admin-e-permessi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/django-admin-e-permessi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.. raw:: html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Capita che a volte framework come &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Django&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; e tool come il suo &#39;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;admin site&#39;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;, ci vengano in mente come scelte per sviluppare velocemente dei CRUD. Tuttavia ci accorgiamo altrettanto velocemente che questo potente strumento propone delle soluzioni che non sempre si sposano con la nostra logica di business. E&#39; questo il caso dei permessi. L&#39;amministrazione di Django non ha il permesso &#39;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;view&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&#39;, o meglio: se un oggetto di buisiness &amp;amp;egrave; visibile da un utente dell&#39;admin site, questo ha anche la possbilit&amp;amp;agrave; di modificarlo.&amp;amp;nbsp;Nelle seguenti verr&amp;amp;agrave; introdotta una possibile soluzione per creare e utilizzare il permesso &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;view&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; all&#39;interno dell&#39;amministrazione di Django, semplificando cos&amp;amp;igrave; la gestione di tutti quegli oggetti su cui la sicurezza del nostro CRUD identifica un gruppo di utenze con il solo diritto di lettura.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;La soluzione suggerita ruota intorno alla classe Django che ha nome di &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Backend.&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; Questa, nelle ultime versioni di Django (v. 1.2), ha subito delle modifiche, dando allo sviluppatore la possibilit&amp;amp;agrave; di subentrare, meno intrusivamente ma pi&amp;amp;ugrave; efficacemente, nel flusso della sicurezza del framework: tanto da poter manipolare i permessi e renderli applicabili esclusivamente a determinati oggetti. Per dettagliare al meglio quali classi create e quali template personalizzare, si rimanda al wiki aziendale &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;wiki.evonove.it&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://wiki.evonove.it&amp;quot;&amp;gt;wiki.evonove.it&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt; nella sessione Django sotto la voce&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;a title=&amp;quot;CustomizeAdminSite&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;http://wiki.evonove.it/Django/CustomizeAdminSite&amp;quot;&amp;gt;CustomizeAdminSite&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;amp;nbsp;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Buona lettura, e se voleste perfezionare o sconvolgere o commentare l&#39;algoritmo proposto siete i ben venuti; sicuro non vi mancano gli strumenti&amp;amp;nbsp;per farlo&amp;amp;nbsp;(wiki, blog, email, ...) .&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;.. raw:: html&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Inauguriamo il blog di Evonove con quella che è forse la più nota (per non dire l&#39;unica) locuzione informatica conosciuta al di fuori del nostro mondo, quello della programmazione software:
&amp;lt;pre&amp;gt;print &#39;hello, world!&#39;&amp;lt;/pre&amp;gt;
E tanto per chiarire quale sarà il tenore tecnico del blog, giusto due parole su quello che sta dietro a queste pagine.

Il progetto è nato insieme alla stessa Evonove ma ha impiegato diverso tempo per venire alla luce. Complice il rincorrersi delle novità che riguardano il nostro lavoro, quella che doveva essere un&#39;unica pagina contenente il minimo indispensabile per consentire ai nostri clienti (attuali e potenziali) di raggiungerci attraverso il Web si è trasformata in una specie di parco giochi per il nostro staff.

Prima l&#39;adozione di un CMS (perché sarebbe stato carino provarlo), poi di un engine per il blog (perché sarebbe stato carino integrarlo), poi una bella iniezione di Javascript (perché sarebbe stato carino aumentare l&#39;interattività). Poi abbiamo smesso di giustificarci ed abbiamo semplicemente continuato a fare quello che ci piace.

Il risultato:
&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Engine CMS basato su django-cms&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Engine Blog basato su django-zinnia&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Custom homepage basata su jQuery e django-cms&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Rendering delle icone via Raphaël Javascript Library&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Tanto bel codice Python per il deployment&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
Nella speranza che i contenuti del blog piacciano, vi invitiamo ad abbonarvi ai nostri feed, riportarci qualche bug e magari far circolare un po&#39; la voce.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django &#43; Wordpress = EvoBlog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/django-wordpress-evoblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2011/django-wordpress-evoblog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ho appena terminato lo switch dell&amp;rsquo;engine che sta dietro al nostro blog:
da django-blog-zinnia siamo passati a Wordpress, prodotto che nell&amp;rsquo;ultimo anno
abbiamo avuto modo di vedere in dettaglio durante lo sviluppo di integrazioni
per alcuni clienti.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zinnia è un ottimo prodotto e sicuramente la migliore app Django che sono
riuscito a trovare che implementi un blog, prendete ad esempio il codice che
serve ad utilizzare &lt;code&gt;Shorty &amp;lt;http://evo9.it&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ come shortener per gli articoli
(a meno del caching che vi risparmio):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. sourcecode:: python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;def backend(entry):
    url = &#39;%s%s&#39; % (Site.objects.get_current().domain,
                        urllib2.quote(entry.get_absolute_url()))
    try:
        f = urllib2.urlopen(&amp;quot;http://www.evo9.it/api/short/%s&amp;quot; % url,
            data=&#39;&#39;)
    except Exception as e:
        return &#39;&#39;
    return json.loads(f.read())
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;E&amp;rsquo; stato altrettanto semplice integrare i contenuti del blog nella homepage del
sito, realizzata con un&amp;rsquo;applicazione Django custom.  Tutto questo però non
riesce a bilanciare le difficoltà di gestione (ad esempio) delle immagini, degli
aggiornamenti, dei contenuti evoluti che a volte vorremmo mettere negli articoli
(codice sorgente formattato). Le motivazioni dello switch sono quindi da
ricercarsi esclusivamente nella facilità con cui Wordpress ci permette di
inserire e modificare gli articoli ed il suo altissimo livello di
SEO-friendlyness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;L&amp;rsquo;integrazione con Django è stata realizzata utilizzando i feed RSS messi a
disposizione da Wordpress, che in questo contesto eccelle. Si tratta di
aggiungere qualcosa del genere alle viste esistenti:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. sourcecode:: python&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;rss_url = &#39;http://www.evonove.it/blog/%s/category/front-page/feed/&#39;
    % context[&#39;lang&#39;]
feed = feedparser.parse(rss_url)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feed vengono recuperati e parsati dalla libreria feedparser: ho barattato
una serie di query al database di backend con una HTTP/GET fatta in localhost,
non ho ancora fatto i benchmark ma ad occhio non mi pare di aver perso nulla in
termini di velocità di elaborazione della pagina.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Django OAuth Toolkit is out!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/django-oauth-toolkit-is-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/django-oauth-toolkit-is-out/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We just released the &lt;code&gt;latest version &amp;lt;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/django-oauth-toolkit/0.3.0&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ of Django OAuth Toolkit,
a library to add OAuth goodies to Django projects. The project is under active development, at the moment it offers
fully-featured and RFC6749 compliant OAuth2 providers implementation and it runs on Django 1.4, 1.5 and 1.6a1 with
Python 2.7 and 3.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;A brief history&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything started when we found ourselves in the need to implement an OAuth2 provider for a Django web service.
We happily use Django REST framework wherever we have to expose an API, and that was right the case. Django REST framework
has built-in support for a third party Django app implementing OAuth providers but we shortly faced some issues and
started to search for an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digging around we stumbled upon this blog post from Daniel Greenfeld:
&lt;code&gt;The sorry state of Python OAuth providers &amp;lt;http://pydanny.com/the-sorry-state-of-python-oauth-providers.html&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_. Enough
is enough but we were still not sure whether starting another project from scratch or not, when we met Daniel at the Django
Circus in Warsaw. We talked shortly about the topic but he was very convincing and we started coding as soon as we came
back at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re trying to involve other people in the project and usually this is the first question we&amp;rsquo;re asked: why another
project? Instead of complaining about other projects, we usually list what we got so far and possibly other don&amp;rsquo;t have:
features and goodies we strongly needed and now actually have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;DRY&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We think &lt;code&gt;oauthlib &amp;lt;https://github.com/idan/oauthlib&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ is currently the state of the art OAuth library in the Python
world. We choose to rely on a well documented, well supported and active project instead of write one on our own, with
all the FUD of the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OAuth protocol can be quite mind boggling every here and there. We think writing good docs is mandatory when the code
may be quite simple but the workflow heavily complicated. We are also putting a lot of efforts on writing tutorials, as
one line of code worths thousand words (expecially with OAuth workflows :-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not referring to Unit testing here (still we do our best to keep coverage over 95% ;-) but to some stuff users
can actually use to test their applications on a real OAuth2 workflow. In some circumstances, OAuth2 applications need
a companion to exchange tokens, provide authorizations and so on. We deployed an OAuth2 playground on Heroku to let
users perform a roundtrip between their local apps and a real server (or client, depending on the case).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Timezone aware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strongly believe that if your dates and times are not timezone aware, they&amp;rsquo;re broken. That said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;Python 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the neverending effort of porting our codebase to Python 3, we cannot rely anymore on libraries and tools which do
not have at least any roadmap for the porting. Django OAuth Toolkit is alredy working with both Python 2.7 and 3.3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re working hard on the project also because we&amp;rsquo;re using it internally in our company, so we can guarantee our full
support on the middle term and hopefully longer, depending on the success it could be have in the Django world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_8&#34;&gt;We want you!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As any other Open Source project, we&amp;rsquo;re nothing without a community: any help is appreciated, code of course but also
docs, testing and any kind of feedback. &lt;code&gt;Fork the project &amp;lt;https://github.com/evonove/django-oauth-toolkit&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_,
take a ride, fill some PRs!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DjangoCon Europe 2013 Wrap-up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/djangocon-europe-2013-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/djangocon-europe-2013-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seriously, a circus? That perfectly fits the quote &lt;em&gt;And now for something completely different&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just got back from the latest DjangoCon Europe - I usually write a sort of log of the conferences I attend, this time
it&amp;rsquo;ll be just a matter of thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. image:: /img/2013/circus.jpg
    :alt: The Circus!
    :align: center
    :class: bordered-img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to the organizers&lt;/strong&gt;, they possibly delivered the craziest tech conference I ever attended. Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;food&lt;/strong&gt;,
I much appreciated the veg option (I arrived in Warsaw prepared to starve, likely I gained weight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. image:: /img/2013/food.jpg
    :alt: Yummy!
    :align: center
    :class: bordered-img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free and fresh beverages&lt;/strong&gt; constantly available for the attendees. Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free beer&lt;/strong&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t now if and when it&amp;rsquo;ll
happen again&amp;hellip;). Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free ice creams&lt;/strong&gt;, again, constantly available during the conference. Thanks for the
&lt;strong&gt;goodies&lt;/strong&gt; (hammoks, blankets, cushions, deckchairs and so on&amp;hellip;). Thanks for bringing me to &lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;: nice people, nice
places, good food - it totally worths, even for a short weekend. Thanks to the &lt;strong&gt;speakers&lt;/strong&gt;, some of them were very
inspiring and the amount of lighting talk was ridicolously huge! Thanks to &lt;code&gt;Emanuele &amp;lt;/authors/palazzem&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ who arranged
a very fun (and informative!) lighting talk in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. image:: /img/2013/lighting.jpg
    :alt: Emanuele on stage
    :align: center
    :class: bordered-img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thanks to the &lt;strong&gt;weather&lt;/strong&gt;, really don&amp;rsquo;t know what could
have been happened in case of rain :-).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Europython 2013 Wrap-up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/europython-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/europython-2013/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Right back from the EuroPython conference, the last in Florence before moving to Berlin for the next two years.
It was a pretty long week, a lot of talks, people, dinners, cocktails, beers, barbecues, sprints&amp;hellip; I just want to
thank the organizers, the wifi guys, the cable guy, the personnel from the hotel, all the nice people I met and
the speakers, in particular those from evonove, who made a great job on contributing with a regular talk, a training
and a lightning talk. We also managed to make a code sprint for
&lt;code&gt;Django OAuth Toolkit &amp;lt;http://github.com/evonove/django-oauth-toolkit&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ on Saturday, right after the goodbye party
(kudos for us :-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the recordings of the talks provided by &lt;code&gt;Emanuele &amp;lt;/authors/palazzem&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ and &lt;code&gt;Federico &amp;lt;/authors/synasius&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Speed up your Django apps with Jython and SPDY&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. youtube:: DD1zLltB1RQ
   :align: center&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;An intro to Blender modeling and scripting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. youtube:: 4e6z3Ada00I
   :align: center&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. youtube:: U1K19GoLMuk
   :align: center&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;An intro to Blender modeling and scripting - Reprise&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. youtube:: 96WoCShO3i0
   :align: center&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the lightning talks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://youtu.be/iUNbgNuN0qY?t=1h9m32s&#34;&gt;http://youtu.be/iUNbgNuN0qY?t=1h9m32s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DjangoCon Europe 2013 Wrap-up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/djangocon-europe-2013-wrap-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/2013/djangocon-europe-2013-wrap-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seriously, a circus? That perfectly fits the quote &lt;em&gt;And now for something completely different&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just got back from the latest DjangoCon Europe - I usually write a sort of log of the conferences I attend, this time
it&amp;rsquo;ll be just a matter of thanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. image:: /img/2013/circus.jpg
    :alt: The Circus!
    :align: center
    :class: bordered-img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thanks to the organizers&lt;/strong&gt;, they possibly delivered the craziest tech conference I ever attended. Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;food&lt;/strong&gt;,
I much appreciated the veg option (I arrived in Warsaw prepared to starve, likely I gained weight).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. image:: /img/2013/food.jpg
    :alt: Yummy!
    :align: center
    :class: bordered-img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free and fresh beverages&lt;/strong&gt; constantly available for the attendees. Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free beer&lt;/strong&gt; (don&amp;rsquo;t now if and when it&amp;rsquo;ll
happen again&amp;hellip;). Thanks for the &lt;strong&gt;free ice creams&lt;/strong&gt;, again, constantly available during the conference. Thanks for the
&lt;strong&gt;goodies&lt;/strong&gt; (hammoks, blankets, cushions, deckchairs and so on&amp;hellip;). Thanks for bringing me to &lt;strong&gt;Warsaw&lt;/strong&gt;: nice people, nice
places, good food - it totally worths, even for a short weekend. Thanks to the &lt;strong&gt;speakers&lt;/strong&gt;, some of them were very
inspiring and the amount of lighting talk was ridicolously huge! Thanks to &lt;code&gt;Emanuele &amp;lt;/authors/palazzem&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;_ who arranged
a very fun (and informative!) lighting talk in a few hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. image:: /img/2013/lighting.jpg
    :alt: Emanuele on stage
    :align: center
    :class: bordered-img&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thanks to the &lt;strong&gt;weather&lt;/strong&gt;, really don&amp;rsquo;t know what could
have been happened in case of rain :-).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>